<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leonardo Ferreira</title>
    <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Leonardo Ferreira</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:30:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ferreirasc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Directory Notes</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/ad_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:30:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/ad_notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AD Notes for Pentesting / RedTeam&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Red Teamer, Pentester, addicted to retrogames and a Megaman fan. I am currently working as a pentester / red teamer at iSecurity Consulting.
Experience  iSecurity Consulting - Oct 2018 - Present (Toronto, Canada Area)
Red Teamer / Penetration Tester
 Conduct technical vulnerability assessments (TVA) and penetration testing in mobile applications (iOS/Android), web applications/APIs, wireless networks (WLAN), external and internal infrastructures. Performed over a dozen of Red Team exercises on both corporate office and industrial plant locations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certified Red Team Expert (CRTE) - Review</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/crte_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 01:33:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/crte_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took the amazing &amp;ldquo;Windows Red Team Lab&amp;rdquo; course from PentesterAcademy, a prerequisite course for the Certified Red Team Expert (CRTE) certification. I must confess that I had my eye on this course for some time, mainly due to the topics covered in its content (anyone who knows me knows how much I like Active Directory exploitation and everything it involves ;). As I was a little tired of the HackTheBox boxes routine, I decided it would be a good time to start the lab and learn new AD stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this review is just to pass on a little of the experience I had in the lab and in the exam. Obviously, I have no intention of providing spoilers, lab walkthrough nor anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>O problema da satisfatibilidade booleana (SAT)</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/spoj_cardapio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 21:10:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/spoj_cardapio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Na teoria da complexidade computacional, o problema da satisfatibilidade booleana (SAT) é reconhecidamente um dos primeiros NP-completo. O problema visa encontrar uma solução verdade para uma dada fórmula booleana, e caso encontrada, a fórmula é considerada “satisfatível”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IO Smash The Stack - Level03</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 01:07:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Com o level 2 concluido, temos acesso ao servidor ssh do level03.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No diretório “/levels”, vemos dois arquivos associados a esse level: level03 e level03.c.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IO Smash The Stack - Level02</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:21:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Com o level01 concluido, obtemos acesso ao shell que nos provê permissões para visualizar a senha do level02.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conectando ao servidor ssh do level2, observamos 4 arquivos associados a esse level: dois binários SUID de 32-bits, level02 e level02_alt, e seus códigos C correspondentes, level02.c e level02_alt.c. Nesse post estarei focando no level02.c e seu binário level02, que é uma das duas formas de concluir esse nível.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IO Smash The Stack - Level01</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 22:01:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/smash_the_stack1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;O “IO Smash The Stack” é um conhecido wargame da Smash The Stack Network. Um “wargame”, na cultura hacker, é o nome dado a um jogo contendo desafios de segurança, geralmente divididos em levels, no quais se deve explorar alguma vulnerabilidade para conseguir acesso aos próximos níveis. Obviamente, a dificuldade dos desafios evolui a cada nível, o que torna as coisas mais divertidas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instalando o sistema BOCA Online Contest</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/boca_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 10:33:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/boca_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neste tutorial estarei demonstrando, passo-a-passo, como instalar e configurar o sistema BOCA Online Contest Administrator, utilizado para criar e gerenciar ambientes para competições de programação.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Este post é direcionado a disciplina de &amp;ldquo;Programação II&amp;rdquo; do curso de Engenharia de Computação da UFES (2014-2), na qual atuo como monitor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programando C em Windows e Linux (Introcomp)</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/introcomp_tutorial01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 18:25:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/post/introcomp_tutorial01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uma breve explicação de como preparar seu ambiente, seja Windows ou Linux, para programar utilizando C. Direcionado aos alunos do Introcomp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://ferreirasc.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferreirasc.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can find me on Telegram: ferreirasc</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>